studydrive.net 2019-06-04

# Privacy Policy - Studydrive

Thank you for your interest in Studydrive!

On Studydrive, we always strive to offer you the best experience possible for studying online, for connecting with your fellow students and for finding the perfect job offer. To achieve this, we collect, store and use personal data and data that is generated when using our platform. 

The security of your data as well as your privacy is very important to us! Therefore, we want to inform you about which data we collect, store and use, how we do this and why. You will find all this information in the following privacy policy. 

Have fun reading! We look forward to meeting you on our platform and wish you all the best for your studies. 

1\. General Information

  * Last updated: 25.05.2018
  * Studydrive GmbH, Mehringdamm 32, 10961 Berlin, Germany is responsible for the processing of personal data

2\. Introduction

Studydrive GmbH, Mehringdamm 32, 10961 Berlin („Studydrive“) operates the internet platform (“platform”) studydrive.net. The Platform can be used on the web page [www.studydrive.net](https://www.studydrive.net/) and through the Mobile Application Studydrive (“App”). 

Users can use this platform to share study materials with other users and exchange information in discussion forums. In addition, users can get information about potential employers and their career offers as well as apply for a job with these companies through a job exchange platform. 

Studydrive collects, processes and uses users’ personal data in accordance with the content of this privacy policy as well as the General Data Protection Regulation (“EU-GDPR”) and the applicable German data protection laws, especially the Bundesdatenschutzgesetz (“BDSG”) as well as the Telemediengesetz („TMG“). 

The following paragraphs present which data are collected, stored and processed by Studydrive via the Studydrive platform. 

This privacy policy applies to the entire service Studydrive and its applications. 

3\. Collection and processing of personal data

Studydrive collects and processes personal data of the users of Studydrive. Personal data within the meaning of these data protection regulations are individual details concerning the personal or factual circumstances as well as the user’s behavior.

3.1 Stock data

3.1.1 Registration via E-Mail

As part of the registration, users are asked to provide some personal information. Studydrive GmbH stores the following user data which are entered during the registration process.

  * First and Last Name
  * University
  * The main subject and the starting semester of the user’s current studies
  * Email address
  * A password
  * Profile picture (optional)

The legal basis for this processing of personal data is Article 6 (1) b) of the EU General Data Protection Regulation (GDPR).

3.1.2 Registration via Facebook Login

Users can register on Studydrive using their Facebook login. This service is provided by Facebook Ireland Limited, 4 Grand Canal Square, Dublin 2, Ireland. 

If users decide to register with Facebook Connect and click on the "Sign up with Facebook" button, they will be automatically redirected to the Facebook platform. There they can log in with their Facebook username and password. This will link their Facebook profile to Studydrive’s website or services. This link gives Studydrive access to the user’s following data stored on Facebook: 

  * Facebook ID
  * Facebook name
  * Facebook profile picture
  * Facebook cover picture
  * Email address provided to Facebook
  * Gender
  * Country
  * Language

This data will be used to set up, provide, and personalize the user’s account. The Facebook ID is needed so that users can login to their Studydrive account after their initial sign up. 

For more information, see Facebook's Terms of Use and Privacy Policy. These can be found at <https://de-de.facebook.com/about/privacy/> and <https://www.facebook.com/legal/terms/>. 

Users need to complete their registration after using the Facebook Login option with the following data:

  * University
  * The main subject and the starting semester of the user’s current studies

The legal basis for this processing of personal data is Article 6 (1) b) of the EU General Data Protection Regulation (GDPR).

3.2 Usage data / Cookies / Third party applications

Studydrive collects data about the usage of the platform by its users in order to improve the platform’s usability and effectiveness and to be able to offer users a customer-tailored service.

3.2.1 Logfiles

The server logs store information submitted by the browser or by the app as users access the platform. The log files contain the following information: 

  * IP address of the computer or the Device ID of a mobile end device
  * Date, time, status, the amount of data transferred, and the web page from which the requested page is accessed (referrer)
  * Product and version information for the browser (user agent), operating system, language settings

The storage of information serves to maintain and improve the platform and their security and to identify and prosecute potentially illegal activities of the users. The log files are anonymized. 

The legal basis for this processing of personal data is Article 6 (1) b) of the EU General Data Protection Regulation (GDPR). 

3.2.2 Cookies and similar technologies

The platform uses cookies and similar technologies. Cookies and similar technologies help make the Studydrive website more user-friendly, efficient, and secure. 

Cookies are small text files that are stored on a user’s computer and saved by the browser. Most of the cookies the platform uses are so-called "session cookies." They are automatically deleted after a user’s visit. Other cookies remain in the device's memory until users delete them. These cookies make it possible to recognize the user’s browser when the user next visits the site. 

A similar technology is used for the Studydrive app, so called Cell-IDs. These allow Studydrive to identify the user’s mobile device, for example when a user opens the app again after the first use. One example: In the Firebase (see above) SDK-library an App Instance ID is used to identify app installations. In general, within the Firebase SDK, IDs of mobile device are identified by a technology that is similar to cookies. 

Users can configure their browser to inform them about the use of cookies so that they can decide on a case-by-case basis whether to accept or reject a cookie. Alternatively, the user’s browser can be configured to automatically accept cookies under certain conditions or to always reject them, or to automatically delete cookies when closing the browser. Disabling cookies may limit the functionality of this website. 

Cookies which are necessary to allow electronic communications or to provide certain functions users wish to use are stored pursuant to Art. 6 paragraph 1, letter f of DSGVO. The website operator has a legitimate interest in the storage of cookies to ensure an optimized service provided free of technical errors. If other cookies (such as those used to analyze your surfing behavior) are also stored, they will be treated separately in this privacy policy. 

3.2.3 Third party applications

Web analytics

a) Studydrive GmbH uses Google Analytics, a web analytics service provided by Google Inc. of 1600 Amphitheater Parkway, Mountain View, CA 94043, USA (Google). Google Analytics also uses cookies to track users' online behaviors, their length of stay, and their sources of reference. The results are transferred to a Google server in the United States of America and stored there. 

Studydrive uses Google Analytics as a tool to analyze how users use the platform. This process is anonymous. 

Users can prevent use of new cookies by using appropriate browser settings (see above). You can also disable Google Analytics by installing a browser add-on provided by Google at: <http://tools.google.com/dlpage/gaoptout?hl=en>. 

Google Inc. is certified under the EU-US Privacy Shield. The Privacy Shield is an agreement between the European Union (EU) and the US to ensure compliance with European privacy standards in the United States. 

For more information about Google Inc. and Google Analytics, please visit [http://www.google.com](http://www.google.com/). Google’s privacy policy can be found on the following website: <https://policies.google.com/privacy>

The legal basis for this processing of personal data is Article 6 (1) f) of the EU General Data Protection Regulation (GDPR). 

b) Studydrive uses Google Firebase on the Studydrive App. Google Firebase a developer platform for mobile applications. Firebase is a service provided by Google Inc. (1600 Amphitheater Parkway, Mountain View, CA 94043, USA, „Google“). 

Studydrive uses the following Firebase services:

  * Google Analytics for Firebase: This is an analytics tool for mobile applications. Studydrive uses this service to analyze how users use the Studydrive app. All data collected and used is anonymized.
  * Firebase Cloud Messaging: Studydrive uses this service to send users of the Studydrive app push notifications on their mobile devices.
  * Firebase Crash Reporting: Studydrive uses this service to collect and analyze error messages which are generated when users encounter errors using the Studydrive app.

Google Inc. is certified under the EU-US Privacy Shield. The Privacy Shield is an agreement between the European Union (EU) and the US to ensure compliance with European privacy standards in the United States. 

For more information about Google Inc., please visit [http://www.google.com](http://www.google.com/). Google’s privacy policy can be found on the following website: <https://policies.google.com/privacy>

The legal basis for this processing of personal data is Article 6 (1) f) of the EU General Data Protection Regulation (GDPR). 

c) Studydrive also uses Google Adwords Conversion Tracking, an analysis service provided by Google Inc. (1600 Amphitheater Parkway, Mountain View, CA 94043, USA, „Google“). Google AdWords will place a cookie on the user's computer („conversion cookie“), provided the user has reached the Studydrive website through a Google ad. These cookies lose their validity after 30 days and are not used for personal identification. If certain pages are visited on Studydrive and the cookie has not yet expired, Studydrive and Google can recognize that someone has clicked on the ad and has been forwarded to the website. Each AdWords customer receives a different cookie. Cookies cannot be tracked through the websites of AdWords customers. The information collected using the conversion cookie is used to create conversion statistics for AdWords customers who have opted for conversion tracking. AdWords customers can see the total number of users who clicked on their ad and were forwarded to a conversion tracking tag. However, they do not receive any information that allows users to be personally identified. If you do not want to participate in the tracking process, you can also refuse the setting of a cookie, for example by using a browser setting, which automatically deactivates the automatic setting of cookies. You can also disable cookies for conversion tracking by setting your browser to block cookies from the domain „googleadservices.com“. 

Google Inc. is certified under the EU-US Privacy Shield. The Privacy Shield is an agreement between the European Union (EU) and the US to ensure compliance with European privacy standards in the United States. 

For more information about Google Inc., please visit [http://www.google.com](http://www.google.com/). Google’s privacy policy can be found on the following website: <https://policies.google.com/privacy>. 

The legal basis for this processing of personal data is Article 6 (1) f) of the EU General Data Protection Regulation (GDPR). 

d) Studydrive uses the Google Inc. remarketing technology (1600 Amphitheater Parkway, Mountain View, CA 94043, USA, „Google“). Through this technology, users who have visited the Internet pages and online services and who have been interested in the offer are addressed again by targeted advertising on the pages of the Google Partner Network. Advertisement is made by the use of cookies, which are small text files that are stored on the user's computer. With the aid of the text files, the user behavior can be analyzed during the visit of the website and then used for targeted product recommendations and interest-based advertising. 

Google Inc. is certified under the EU-US Privacy Shield. The Privacy Shield is an agreement between the European Union (EU) and the US to ensure compliance with European privacy standards in the United States. 

For more information about Google Inc., please visit [http://www.google.com](http://www.google.com/). Google’s privacy policy can be found on the following website: <https://policies.google.com/privacy>. 

The legal basis for this processing of personal data is Article 6 (1) f) of the EU General Data Protection Regulation (GDPR). 

e) Studydrive uses Mixpanel, a web analytics service provided by Mixpanel, Inc., 589 Howard Street, #4 San Francisco, CA 94105, USA. Studydrive uses Mixpanel as a tool to analyze how users use the website and the app. Studydrive also uses Mixpanel to send users push notifications on their mobile devices. 

Statistical data about usage of the website and app are analyzed to improve the performance and functionality as well as the usability of the service. Mixpanel uses cookies and pixels that are implemented on web and app pages. 

Mixpanel, Inc. is certified under the EU-US Privacy Shield. The Privacy Shield is an agreement between the European Union (EU) and the US to ensure compliance with European privacy standards in the United States. 

Users can prevent collection and usage of their data through Mixpanel by using the optout function on this webpage: <https://mixpanel.com/optout/>. 

The legal basis for this processing of personal data is Article 6 (1) f) of the EU General Data Protection Regulation (GDPR). 

f) Studydrive uses the “visitor action pixel“ of Facebook Inc., 1601 S. California Ave, Palo Alto, CA 94304, USA („Facebook“). Through this pixel, users' behavior can be tracked after they have been redirected to Studydrive's website by clicking on a Facebook ad. This process is designed to evaluate the effectiveness of Facebook advertising for statistical and market research purposes and can help to optimize future advertising. The collected data are anonymous, so they do not provide any conclusions about the identity of users. However, the Facebook data is stored and processed so that it can be connected to the respective user profile, and Facebook can use the data for its own advertising purposes, according to the Facebook Data Usage Guideline (<https://www.facebook.com/about/privacy/> ). You can enable Facebook as well as its partners to show ads inside and outside of Facebook. It is also possible, that a cookie is stored on your computer for these purposes. 

Users can also deactivate the custom audiences remarketing feature in the Ads Settings section at <https://www.facebook.com/ads/preferences/?entry_product=ad_settings_screen>. They will first need to log into Facebook. 

If users do not have a Facebook account, they can opt out of usage-based advertising from Facebook on the website of the European Interactive Digital Advertising Alliance: <http://www.youronlinechoices.com/de/praferenzmanagement/>. 

The legal basis for this processing of personal data is Article 6 (1) f) of the EU General Data Protection Regulation (GDPR). 

Plugins

Studydrive uses plugins (e.g., the ‘Share Button') from the Facebook Inc., 1601 S. California Ave, Palo Alto, CA 94304, USA. When you open the web page with a plug-in, the browser will automatically connect to the Facebook servers. Studydrive GmbH is not able to adapt or control the connection of the plugin. Through the plugins, Facebook can collect information about visited websites and brings this information to the Facebook accounts of the users. Studydrive GmbH can neither influence nor assume any responsibility for the content of the plugins and the data transmitted to the Facebook server. Should users need more information about how Facebook handles personal data, you can consult their privacy policy at [www.facebook.com/policy.php](https://www.facebook.com/policy.php). If users want to prevent Facebook from gathering data and information, they must log out of Facebook before they visit the platform or delete all Facebook cookies. 

The legal basis for this processing of personal data is Article 6 (1) a) of the EU General Data Protection Regulation (GDPR).

Newsletter / Email notifications

Studydrive uses the services of Mailgun to send emails. This service is provided by Mailgun Technologies, 535 Mission St., 14th Floor, San Francisco, CA 94105, USA. 

Mailgun is a service which organizes and analyzes the distribution of newsletters. In order to send personalized emails and newsletter to users, personal data like users’ names and email address will be stored on Mailgun servers in the USA. 

Mailgun is certified under the EU-US Privacy Shield. The Privacy Shield is an agreement between the European Union (EU) and the US to ensure compliance with European privacy standards in the United States. 

Studydrive uses Mailgun to analyze newsletter and email campaigns. When users open an email sent by Mailgun, a file included in the email (called a web beacon) connects to Mailgun's servers in the United States. This allows Studydrive to determine if an email message has been opened and which links users click on. In addition, technical information is collected (e.g. time of retrieval, IP address, browser type, and operating system). This information cannot be assigned to a specific recipient. It is used exclusively for the statistical analysis of our newsletter campaigns. The results of these analyses can be used to better tailor future newsletters and emails to users’ interests. 

If users do not want their usage of newsletters to be analyzed by Mailgun, users will have to unsubscribe from the newsletter. For this purpose, we provide a link in every newsletter we send. Users can also unsubscribe from the newsletter directly on the website in their settings. 

Data processing is based on Art. 6 (1) (b) DSGVO for emails which are linked to the execution of the usage contract, and is based on Art. 6 (1) (a) DSGVO for Newsletters, which users subscribed to via opt-in. 

Users may revoke their consent to newsletters at any time by unsubscribing from the newsletter or email campaigns. More information on how to unsubscribe from newsletter and email campaigns are detailed in paragraph 4.1.1 of this privacy policy. The data processed before Studydrive receives a user’s request may still be legally processed. 

The data provided when registering for a newsletter will be used to distribute mails until users cancel their subscription when said data will be deleted from our servers and those of Mailgun. Data we have stored for other purposes (e.g. email addresses for the members area) remains unaffected. 

For details, see the Mailgun privacy policy at [https://Mailgun.com/legal/terms/.Live-Chat](https://mailgun.com/legal/terms/.Live-Chat)

On studydrive.net, users can communicate with Studydrive employees via live chat. Studydrive uses the service Userlike for this purpose. The service is provided by the Userlike UG (haftungsbeschränkt), Probsteingasse 44-46, 50670 Köln, Germany. 

Userlike collects, stores and uses data that users enter when using the service: Name, email address and the chat messages. Userlike also uses Cookies to enable the live chat and collects, stores and uses the following additional data: Date und Time of usage, browser type and version, the operation system used, URL of the previously visited webpage and the amount of data collected. This data is only stored for technical reasons and are not attributed to a specific person. This data is deleted as soon as the internet session of the user ends. 

Users can disable cookies by setting the appropriate settings in their browser (as outlined in paragraph 3.2.2 of this privacy policy). 

Studydrive does not store data collected by Userlike but has access to this data in the Studydrive account on Userlike’s webpage. 

This data processing is based on Art. 6 (1) (a) DSGVO. 

Users can find more information about Userlike and their usage of data in Userlike’s privacy policy: <https://www.userlike.com/de/terms#privacy-policy>

3.3 Content data

Content data is data that users upload or post to the platform. These are, for example, the documents that users upload, the questions, answers and comments they post, and the content they make accessible to other users or generally accessible. Studydrive GmbH will not pass these data on to third parties. However, the content is accessible to other users and can be downloaded and copied by them.

4\. Usage of data

Studydrive GmbH uses the data to offer its services to their users via their platform and to ensure the functionality of the platform. The contact data provided by the users serves to contact the users and manage the user account at Studydrive GmbH.

4.1 Stock data

4.1.1 Usage of stock data

The first name and surname, as well as the educational path, are visible to all other users. The e-mail address and the self-chosen password remain secret. 

Users are informed about changes and updates on Studydrive through the email address provided upon registration. Users also receive notifications for jobs, career events and general career information offered by our partner companies. 

Users can at any time unsubscribe from email notifications by sending an e-mail to [info@studydrive.net](mailto:info@studydrive.net) or by logging into their studydrive account and changing their email settings on this website: <https://www.studydrive.net/settings>. 

The legal basis for this processing of personal data is Article 6 (1) b) of the EU General Data Protection Regulation (GDPR). 

4.1.2 Search functions and active feeds

A part of users’ personal information is accessible for and searchable by other users. This information includes the specified name or pseudonym and the specified university.

4.1.3 Comments

Users can leave comments and discuss with other users on the platform. Users can decide to post anonymously or with their chosen name. If users posts a comment and choose to post via their chosen name on Studydrive, the name will be visible for other users on Studydrive.

4.2 Usage data

Studydrive GmbH is always striving to improve the platform for its users. Therefore, it determines how the platform is used to identify usage patterns, peak usage times, and the popularity of certain offers and features. 

The data thus obtained is used to implement technical adaptations and functional improvements for the users. The use of analytical tools and cookies is therefore crucial to provide users with an excellent service. The collected information can help improve the platform for the users. 

4.3 Content data

4.3.1 Accessibility of content

Users alone have control over the content they want to upload and make accessible to other users. This includes all kinds of files, comments and personal data. Studydrive GmbH merely provides the technical requirements and is not responsible for the actions of its users. If a user decides to upload material or information from third parties, he or she is solely responsible. The extent to which information is shared is not influenced by Studydrive GmbH. Therefore, only users decide which content they make accessible.

4.3.2 Course and group proposals and data comparison

Users can join different courses and groups on Studydrive. Studydrive compares the content of the booked courses and groups with other courses and groups, in order to propose further courses and groups.

5\. Information about users’ rights

5.1 Right to file complaints with regulatory authorities

If there has been a breach of data protection legislation, the person affected may file a complaint with the competent regulatory authorities. The competent regulatory authority for matters related to data protection legislation is the data protection officer of the German state in which Studydrive GmbH is headquartered. A list of data protection officers and their contact details can be found at the following link: <https://www.bfdi.bund.de/DE/Infothek/Anschriften_Links/anschriften_links-node.html>.

5.2 Right to data portability

You have the right to have data which we process based on your consent or in fulfillment of a contract automatically delivered to yourself or to a third party in a standard, machine-readable format. If you require the direct transfer of data to another responsible party, this will only be done to the extent technically feasible.

5.3 Information and deletion of accounts

As permitted by law, you have the right to be provided at any time with information free of charge about any of your personal data that is stored as well as its origin, the recipient and the purpose for which it has been processed. You also have the right to have this data corrected, blocked or deleted. You can contact us at any time using the address given in our legal notice if you have further questions on the topic of personal data.

Thank you for reading our privacy policy! If you have any questions about our policy, you can always contact us at [info@studydrive.net](mailto:info@studydrive.net).

See you soon on Studydrive and good luck with your studies!
